A Guide to The Papers of Clifton Waller Barrett,
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The Papers of Clifton Waller Barrett
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6526-b
This collection consists of ca. 400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited in the library on 10 Jan. 1974 [1962].
Contents List
- Series I: Materials relating to Mr. Barrett's collecting efforts, 16 Hollinger boxes
  Boxes contain some purchase records, book lists, and catalogs, correspondence with universities, learned societies and dealers, speeches and articles by Mr. Barrett, and various records of his gifts.
  - Blueprint for a Basic Library 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Some Bibliographical Adventure in Americana 1950 (Box 1)
  - Speech for the Antiquarian Booksellers Association 1950 (Box 1)
  - Henry Adams 1951 (Box 1)
  - Introduction of Robert Frost at University of Virginia 1952 Oct. 10 (Box 1)
  - Remarks at dinner to Ambassador de la Campa 1952 Oct. 17 (Box 1)
  - Speech at luncheon for the Cuban Ambassador 1952 Oct. 21 (Box 1)
  - Speech on book-collecting delivered at the University of Pennsylvania 1952 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
  - Beyond the Book 1952 (Box 1)
  - Gleanings in a Field of Stubble 1952 (Box 1)
  - Articles for Exporters' Digest 1953 (Box 1)
  - Remarks for the Cuban Chamber 1953 June 10 (Box 1)
  - The Stephen Crane Society at Lafayette 1953 (Box 1)
  - Speech re: expansion of Nassau Hospital [ca.1953] (Box 1)
  - Speech for the Cuban Chamber 1954 June 3 (Box 1)
  - American Fiction: The First Seventy-Five Years 1954 (Box 1)
  - The Barrett Collection 1956 (Box 1)
  - Collecting the Books We Grew Up With 195[7?] May 6 (Box 1)
  - Two Letters from Mark Twain and Walt Whitman on the Civil War 1957 (Box 1)
  - Washington Irving: Our First Literary Ambassador 1957 (Box 1)
  - "Can the Rich Write?" by Geoffrey T. Hellman 1958 (Box 1)
  - Review of A Bibliography of Henry James by Leon Edel and Dan H. Laurence 1958 (Box 1)
  - Re: The Anatomy of Freedom by Judge Harold Medina 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Speech on Whittier for American Antiquarian Society 1958 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re: Lectures at Berkeley 1959 (Box 1)
  - "The Motivations of a Private Collector....," Presented to the A.L.A. at Folger Library 1959 (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Fifty Years of Collecting Americana.... By Clarence Brigham 1959 (Box 1)
  - Some American Writers and the Civil War 1959 (Box 1)
  - Untitled Speech [1960?] (Box 1)
  - The Growth of Southern Literature 1961 Nov. 3 (Box 1)
  - How to Collect a First Edition [ca.1961] (Box 2)
  - 268 Years of Book Collecting 1962 Jan. 19 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Society 1962 Sept. 22 (Box 2)
  - Introduction of Eraskine Caldwell 1962 Oct. 4 (Box 2)
  - Introduction of John Dos Passos 1963 March 14 (Box 2)
  - Talk before Jared Elliott Society 1963 April 23 (Box 2)
  - Address at the University of North Carolina 1963 May 3 (Box 2)
  - Speech concerning the Patrons and Sponsors of the Poetry Society of America 1963 (Box 2)
  - The American Literary Background of George Washington's Time 1965 Oct. 23 (Box 2)
  - Adventures in Rare Books and Manuscripts 1965 Nov. 4 (Box 2)
  - American Writers in England 1968 March 14 (Box 2)
  - Address to the American Surgical Association: some sidelights on the History of Medicine at the University of Virginia 1975 Jan. 18 (Box 2)
  - Adventures in Book Collecting n. d. (Box 2)
  - Carroll A. Wilson n. d. (Box 2)
  - Copies of several speeches/articles n. d. (Box 2)
  - Do you Buy and Read the Right Novels n. d. (Box 2)
  - Good-bye to Wall Street n. d. (Box 2)
  - Introduction of Robert Frost n. d. (Box 2)
  - New Orleans Journal n. d. (Box 2)
  - A Note on the Disenchanted Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald n. d. (Box 2)
  - The Collector and the Libraian n. d. (Box 2)
  - Untitled Speech n. d. (Box 2)
  - The Fourth Diminsion of Library Sciences n. d. (Box 2)
  - Untitled Speech n. d. (Box 2)
  - How to Present a Book n. d. (Box 2)
  - Henry Adams and the Making of a History n. d. (Box 2)
  - Italian Influence on American Literature n. d. (Box 2)
  - Two Early American Collectors of Italian Act n. d. (Box 2)
  - The Growth of Southern Literature n. d. (Box 2)
  - Preface to Catalogue of the First Edition of American Authorsn. d. (Box 2)
  - Speech on some of the correspondence of Irving Hawthorne, Longfellow, Whitman, Twain and Frost n. d. (Box 2)
  - The Spirit of Southern Literature n. d. (Box 2)
  - Clifton Waller Barrett's Personal Notes, Correspondence, and Papers ca.1957-1963, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with John T. Winterich ca.1953-1957 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Jacob Blanck ca.1952-1959 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence between CWn, book dealers and Alderman Library 1949-1966, 11 folders (Box 4)
  - Clippings re: Barrett Room ca.1945-1966 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence re: Barrett Room ca.1955-1965, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Plans for the Barrett Room 1957-1960, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - First proofs of A Brief Account of The Clifton Waller Barrett Libraryca.1960 (Box 5)
  - Photos taken at addication of Barrett Room 1960 (Box 5)
  - Gifts given in honor of Barrett Room Opening 1960 (Box 5)
  - Guest lists for Barrett Room Opening 1960 (Box 5)
  - Speeches for opening of Barrett Library 1960 April 30 (Box 5)
  - Photos of C. W. Barrett's 70th Birthday Party 1971 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence re: C. W. Barrett's 70 Birthday Party 1971 (Box 5)
  - Guest list for C. W. Barrett's 70th Birthday Party 1971 (Box 5)
  - Friends of the Columbia Libraries 1955-1963, 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Grolier Club 1943; 1947-1954, 10 folders (Box 7)
  - Grolier Club 1955-1960, 8 folders (Box 8)
  - Grolier Club 1961, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Grolier Club: Italian Exhibit photographs 1961, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Grolier Club 1962, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Alderman Library Correspondence 1948-1963 (Box 11)
  - America-Italy Society 1961-1963 (Box 11)
  - American Antiquarian Society 1950-1962 (Box 11)
  - American Library in Paris 1957-1962, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Bibliographical Society of America 1949-1962 (Box 11)
  - Century Club 1957-1962 (Box 11)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1959-1961 (Box 11)
  - Harvard University 1952-1962 (Box 11)
  - Henry Holt Publishing Company 1959-1963 (Box 11)
  - John Carter Brown Library 1957-1963 (Box 11)
  - Lawrenceville School 1955-1963 (Box 11)
  - Massachusetts Historical Society 1957-1960 (Box 11)
  - MLA Conference re: Scholarly Editions of American Authors 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - New York Public Libraries 1956-1963 (Box 11)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library 1954-1963 (Box 11)
  - Poetry Society of America 1956-1963 (Box 11)
  - Princeton University 1953-1962 (Box 11)
  - The Rowfant Club 1962 (Box 12)
  - Shakespeare Association of America 1962 (Box 12)
  - Union Club 1958-1963 (Box 12)
  - University of Virginia and University of Virginia Alumni Association 1950-1961 (Box 12)
  - University of Virginia Alumni Fund 1960-1963 (Box 12)
  - The White House Library 1963 (Box 12)
  - Winterthur Museum 1960-1963 (Box 12)
  - Yale University 1953-1963 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous: Club, Association Correspondence ca. 1952-1963, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous: Book, Library, etc. Correspondence ca.1941-1963, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Barrett House: Florence Crittenton League, etc. 1957-1959 (Box 14)
  - Beekman-Downtown Hospital 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Business Affairs: Steamship Co. 1955-1963 (Box 14)
  - Cuban Affairs 1954-1958 (Box 14)
  - Farmington Country Club 1957-1962 (Box 14)
  - Financial Business ca.1953-1963, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Lake Placid 1959-1963 (Box 14)
  - National Golf Links of America 1953-1959 (Box 14)
  - Westhampton Country Club 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Henry Adams and the Making of a History n. d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Henry Adams and the Making of a History-Notes and Miscellaneous Correspondence n. d. (Box 15)
  - Copies of William Wirt - Thomas Jefferson Correspondence n. d. (Box 15)
  - Copies of Adams' letters n. d. (Box 15)
  - Electrostatic copies of appraisals by Seven Gables ca.1958-1971, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Electrostatic copies of various dealers' invoices ca.1960-1970, 3 folders (Box 16)
- Series II: Financial records of Mr. Barrett, 8 cubic ft. boxes.
  - Checks
    - A large number of blank check-record books of First National City Bank 1952-59 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Cancelled checks of First National City Bank 1952-59 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - A checkbook w/blank checks, The National City Bank of N. Y. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Checks, First National City Bank 1952-62 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Checks 1957-61 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Fifteen hardbound check-record books of First National City Bank 1960-62 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Bank Statements and trust records from First National City Bank
    - Report on Security Holdings of C. W. Barrett 1939 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Report on Security Holdings of C. W. Barrett 1940 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Report on Security Holdings of C. W. Barrett and Cornelia H. Barrett 1941 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Report on Security Holdings of C. W. Barrett 1942 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Report on Security Holdings of C. W. Barrett 1944 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - White envelop, marked "Hand Deliver," contains copies of trust agreements in favor of C.W.B., Jr. 1947 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - A large brown envelope, no title, contains investment account records from First National City Bank, 1946-48, and brokerage confirmation slips (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Report on Security Holdings of Cornelia H. Barrett and C. W. Barrett 1948 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Report on Security Holdings of Cornelia H. Barrett and C. W. Barrett 1949 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Various investment and trust records, mainly from First National City Bank, found loose, here bound as "Trust Account," 1948-50 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Report on Security Holdings of Cornelia H. Barrett and C. W. Barrett 1950 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Report on Security Holdings of Cornelia H. Barrett and C. W. Barrett 1955 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Bank Statements 1955 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - City Bank Farmers Trust Company 1955-56 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - First National City Bank of N. Y. 1955 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - City Bank Farmers Trust Co. 1957-59 (Box-folder 3:16)
    - First National City Bank, Park Ave.-57th Street 1957-60 (Box-folder 3:17)
    - City Bank Farmers Trust Company 1956-58 (Box-folder 3:18)
    - Richard T. and Robert P. Barrett Investment Advisory Accounts 1958-59, with First National City Bank (Box-folder 3:19)
    - Jon Sherwood Barrett, Investment Records 1958-60 (Box-folder 3:20)
    - Robert S. and Viola Barrett Estate 1960 (Box-folder 3:21)
    - First National City Trust Company 1958-59 (Box-folder 3:22)
    - First National City Trust Company 1959-62 (Box-folder 3:23)
    - First National City Bank 1960, also some 1958-59 (Box-folder 3:24)
    - First National City Bank and Trust Company 1961 (Box-folder 3:25)
    - First National City Bank, 57 and Park 1961-62 (Box-folder 3:26)
    - First National City Bank 1962 (Box-folder 3:27)
    - First National City Bank and Trust 1963 (Box-folder 3:28)
    - C. W. Barrett, Guardian for Kate Waller Barrett 1961-63 (Box-folder 3:29)
    - Invoices, etc., C. W. Barrett, Personal 1937 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Statements - Miscellaneous 1946-52 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Statements - Miscellaneous 1953 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Statements - Miscellaneous 1954 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - A brown cardboard expanding file marked "C. W. B. Personal Bills, 1957" (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Personal Bills, A - K 1958 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Personal Bills, L - Z 1958 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Personal Bills, A - I 1959 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Personal Bills, J - Z 1959 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Personal Bills, A - D 1960 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Personal Bills, D - K 1960 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Personal Bills, L - Q 1960 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Personal Bills, R - Z 1960 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Paid Bills, A - C 1961 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Paid Bills, D - L 1961 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Paid Bills, M - Z 1961 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Personal Bills 1962 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Personal Bills 1962 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Investment records from First National City Bank, but mainly brokerage confirmations from Walter Murphy, Jr. Company and others 1942-48 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Mainly stock brokerage confirmations from First National City Bank 1940-60 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Bookplates of Clifton Waller Barrett, business cards from various associates, etc. 1940-60 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Investment records from First National City Bank, some financial papers relating to University of Virginia Alumni and Lake Placid Clubs, brokerage statements 1959-63 (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Investment records from First National City Bank, some financial papers relating to University of Virginia Alumni and Lake Placid Clubs, brokerage statements, etc. 1945-63 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - A. M. Kidder and Company: Brokerage account, especially trading in Long Island Trust Company stock 1956 (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett - 500 shares Dow Chemical Stock 1954 (Box-folder 6:7)
    - One Manhattan telephone directory, white pages only 1963-64 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Insurance Policies and Tax Records
    - Envelopes for Guardians Life Insurance Company, policies themselves not present 1930 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Life and accident insurance policies on Clifton Waller Barrett with three different companies 1930 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Confidential Life Insurance Analysis prepared for Clifton Waller Barrett by agent of Provident Mutual Company (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Insurance matters - Tunmore, expired 1950 (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Aetna Life Insurance Company, expired 1956-58 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Expired Insurance matters 1956-60 (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Automobile Insurance Policies 1937-48 (Box-folder 7:7)
    - Income Tax Return 1936-37 (Box-folder 7:8)
    - Tax Papers 1950 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - Tax File 1951 (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Household Employee Records 1951-53 (Box-folder 7:11)
    - Tax File 1952 (Box-folder 7:12)
    - Tax File 1953 (Box-folder 7:13)
    - Employer's Quarterly Tax Return 1953-54 (Box-folder 7:14)
    - Tax File 1954 (Box-folder 7:15)
    - Tax File 1955 (Box-folder 7:16)
    - Property Taxes 1946-55 (Box-folder 7:17)
    - Tax Returns 1956 (Box-folder 7:18)
    - Moneys Received 1956 (Box-folder 7:19)
    - Taxes, Interest, etc. 1956 (Box-folder 7:20)
    - Contributions 1956 (Box-folder 7:21)
    - Stock Contributions 1956 (Box-folder 7:22)
    - Tax File 1956 (Box-folder 7:23)
    - Tax File 1957 (Box-folder 7:24)
    - Tax Returns, Federal and State 1958 (Box-folder 7:25)
    - Internal Revenue 1958 (Box-folder 7:26)
    - Medical Expenses 1958 (Box-folder 7:27)
    - Deductions 1958 (Box-folder 7:28)
    - Federal Tax on Memberships and Entertainment 1958 (Box-folder 7:29)
    - Taxes 1958 (Box-folder 7:30)
    - Memberships - Deductible 1958 (Box-folder 7:31)
    - Moneys Received 1958 (Box-folder 7:32)
    - Contributions 1958 (Box-folder 7:33)
    - Stock Donations 1958 (Box-folder 7:34)
  - Tax Records
    - Taxes 1959 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Taxes 1960 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Federal and N. Y. State taxes 1960 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Moneys Received 1960 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Taxes 1960 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Tax Returns 1960 (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Winwell Loss 1960 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Medical Expenses 1960 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Contributions 1960 (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Stock Contributions 1960 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Contributions and Memberships 1960 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - IRS Re-Audit of 1960-61 Tax (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Federal and N. Y. Forms 1961 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Papers returned by Arthur Young 1961 (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Winwell 1959 and 1961 (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Federal and N. Y. State Tax Returns 1961 (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Stock Contributions 1961 (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Contributions 1961 (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Moneys Received 1961 (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Taxes Paid on Real Estate 1961 (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Income Taxes Paid 1961 (Box-folder 8:21)
    - Interest Paid on Loans, Rent, Salaries, etc. 1961 (Box-folder 8:22)
    - Medical Expenses 1961 (Box-folder 8:23)
    - 2 Ledger books, with notations for expenses, loans, etc.; kept apparently for tax purposes ca.1961 (Box-folder 8:24 & 25)
    - Tax Papers returned by Accountant 1962 (Box-folder 8:26)
    - Federal and State Income Tax 1962 (Box-folder 8:27)
    - Stock Contributions (Box-folder 8:28)
    - Estimated Tax Returns, Federal and N. Y. 1962 (Box-folder 8:29)
    - Contributions 1962 (Box-folder 8:30)
    - Contributions 1962 (Box-folder 8:31)
    - Taxes Paid on Real Estate 1962 (Box-folder 8:32)
    - Moneys Received 1962 (Box-folder 8:33)
    - Interest Paid on Loans, Rent, Salaries, etc. 1962 (Box-folder 8:34)
    - Payroll Book and Forms 1962 (Box-folder 8:35)
    - Tax Losses 1962 (Box-folder 8:36)
    - Westhampton, Arrangements for rental, etc. 1957-62 (Box-folder 8:37)
    - Westhampton House Sale 1962 (Box-folder 8:38)
    - Taxes Estimated - Winwell Tax Gain and Loss 1962 (Box-folder 8:39)
    - Pending Contributions and Payments 1961-63 (Box-folder 8:40)
    - Pledges, Gifts 1964 (Box-folder 8:41)
- Series III: Business, Financial and Family papers of Mr. Barrett., 3 green transfer cases
  This group consists of personal correspondence, family history, business records of interest, and personal affairs such as University of Virginia activties and the Lake Placid Club
  - Personal papers and correspondence, arranged alphabetically and chronologically by folder headings.
    Included are two business concerns of special importance in Mr. Barrett's career: his steamship companies and the Holt publishing company
    - Articles and Speeches by Clifton Waller Barrett which do not relate to collecting 1949-54 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett - Personal 1937 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett, Sr., Correspondence with Family Members 1950-54 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Barrett Family Genealogy and other information n. d. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett, Sr., Personal Data and other information, 1952 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett, Jr. 1941-52 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Kate Waller Barrett 1946 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Viola Tupper Barrett, contains an original typed manuscript by VTB about 5000 words, Rusty's R's or Calling All Dream-Mothersn. d. (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Barrett Family 1956-59 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Barrett Family 1959-60 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Barrett Family 1960-63 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - The Barrett Foundation 1959-60 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - The Barrett Foundation 1960-62 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - "C" 1950-54 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Cathedral of the Incarnation 1950-54 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Florence Crittenton League, Inc. 1930-52 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Cuban Chamber of Commerce in the U. S. 1950-51 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Cuban Chamber of Commerce in the U. S. 1952-53 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Cuban Chamber of Commerce in the U. S. 1954 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Cuban Chamber of Commerce in the U. S. 1957-59 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Cuban Chamber of Commerce Publicity Committee 1956 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Foreign Policy Association 1957-58 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Foreign Policy Luncheon to Morse 1957 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - "H" 1950-55 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1948-50 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1951 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1952-53 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1954 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1957-58 (Box-folder 1:29)
    - Henry Holt and Company, Stock Agreement 1956-59 (Box-folder 1:30)
    - Henry Holt and Company, Stock Agreement April 1958 (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Henry Holt and Company 1959-60 (Box-folder 1:32)
    - Holt Rinehart and Winston, Inc. 1960-61 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - Holt Rinehart and Winston, Inc. 1962 (Box-folder 1:34)
    - Holt Rinehart and Winston, Inc. 1963 (Box-folder 1:35)
    - India House Application 1946-54 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - Interoffice Memos 1950-54 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - "I" 1952-54 (Box-folder 1:38)
    - The Virginia Masonic Herald March, 1942 (Box-folder 1:39)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Circulars 1942 (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Photographs, contains only one photo, Clifton Waller Barrett w/two other men, plus cover letter from John Cook Wyllie 1952 (Box-folder 1:41)
    - Properties in Charlottesville: 1952 (Box-folder 1:42)
      - A copy of the architect's plans for "Arcadia"
      - Coles and Richmond 1952
      - William S. Downing, Jr., Mr. Barrett's architect, 1952-54
      - Roy Wheeler Realty Co., 1952
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, A - Z, 1952
    - Properties in New York: (Box-folder 1:43)
      - Culver, Hollyday, and Company, Inc., 1953
      - Douglas L. Elliman and Company, Inc., 1950-53
    - Saturday Review January, 1960 (Box-folder 1:44)
    - Sons of the Revolution 1936-37 (Box-folder 1:45)
    - Steamship Companies 1950-59 (Box-folder 1:46)
    - University of Virginia: (Box-folder 1:47)
      - Alumni Fund 1960-61
      - Alumni Association, New York Chapter, 1952
      - Development Fund 1947-53
      - George O. Ferguson, Jr., Dean of Admissions 1949-51
      - Richard R. Fletcher, Director of Admissions 1952-53
      - Phi Beta Kapa, Beta of Va. 1952
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, A - Z 1947-53
    - U. Va. II, Mr. Barrett's yacht 1952-59 (Box-folder 1:48)
  - Investments
    - Alexandria Improvement Corporation 1956 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - American Heritage Publishing Co., Inc. 1961 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Antillian Steel Corporation 1957-58 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Basic Incorporated 1956-58 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Clean-O-Matic Services, Inc. 1962 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Commerce Clearing House, Inc. 1961 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Coastal States Gas Producing Co. 1958-59 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - The Crowell-Collier Publishing Co. 1957-58 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Cuban Bagasse Products, S. A. 1958-59 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Cuban Stock Losses 1963 (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Delta Capitol Corporation 1962 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Digitronics Corp. 1960 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Eastern Broadcasting Corporation 1958-63 (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Federal Street Fund, Inc. 1961 (Box-folder 2:14)
    - First Charter Financial Corporation 1959 (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Harris-Intertype Corporation 1962 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Ideal Precision Meter Co., Inc. 1962 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - Clifton Waller Barrett - Provisional Certificates, Cia Inspiracion Cubana de Cobre. 1952-55 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - A. M. Kidder and Co. 1961 (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Kidder, Peabody and Co. 1956-58 (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Kidder, Peabody and Co. 1957-60 (Box-folder 2:21)
    - Kingsport Press, Inc. 1960 (Box-folder 2:22)
    - Lake Ontario Portland Cement Co. 1959-60 (Box-folder 2:23)
    - Long Island Trust Company 1955-57 (Box-folder 2:24)
    - McLouth Steel Corporation 1957-61 (Box-folder 2:25)
    - Maritime Coal and Coke Corp. 1955-58 (Box-folder 2:26)
    - Mid-America Pipeline Co. 1960 (Box-folder 2:27)
    - Miscellaneous Investments 1957 (Box-folder 2:28)
    - Pocket Books, Inc. 1961 (Box-folder 2:29)
    - Producing Properties, Inc. 1958-62 (Box-folder 2:30)
    - Row, Peterson and Co. 1960 (Box-folder 2:31)
    - Scott Foreman and Co. 1960 (Box-folder 2:32)
    - Small Business Investment Co. 1961 (Box-folder 2:33)
    - Smith Barney and Co. 1961 (Box-folder 2:34)
    - Socony Mobil Oil Company, Inc. 1959 (Box-folder 2:35)
    - Spencer Trask and Company 1954-56 (Box-folder 2:36)
    - Spencer Trask and Company 1956-58 (Box-folder 2:37)
    - Trans-Cuba Oil Company 1958 (Box-folder 2:38)
    - H. C. Wainwright and Co. 1956 (Box-folder 2:39)
    - West Indies Perlite Manufacturing Corp. 1958-59 (Box-folder 2:40)